Oh my goodness. I am super excited about
today. It's another blue day. It's the
conclusion of week one. It's a project
day. It's just going to be so great.
Yeah, this week is meant to be about
vibe coding for fun and profit. I feel
like we've done plenty of fun. It's time
to look at the profit side of things.
We're going to build a commercial MVP of
a product that perhaps you could
monetize and we're going to do it with
Vibe Coding. And I feel like yesterday I
talked you through the rules of the
road, how to be successful with vibe
coding and then I broke all the rules by
just yoloing and not watching what was
happening. Well, today we are going to
follow the rules and you're going to see
how that leads to successful outcomes.
But first, I want to take you through a
series of tweets from Andre Karpathy,
the amazing Andre Karpathy, the some of
which we've already seen, but I want to
take you through them in in order of of
when they came out in chronological
order. This tweet was the one I showed
you before, which was when Andre coined
the term vibe coding. There's a new kind
of coding where you give in fully to the
vibes, embrace the exponentials, forget
that the code even exists. It's possible
because the LLMs are getting too good.
So there you have it. And Andre mentions
cursor composer and set. And now we will
take his next tweet in this series.
Yeah, that was from February of last
year. Then this came at the end of the
year and this was how I opened up the
course. If you remember, this was
Andre's kind of explosion of what's
going on. I've never felt this much
behind as a programmer. I feel like I
could be 10x more powerful if I could
just string together what's going on
involving agents, sub aents, prompts,
contexts, memory, modes, permissions,
tools, plugins, skills, hooks, MCP, LSP/
workflows, IDE integrations, and a need
for an all-encompassing mental model.
That was Carpathy's tweet that inspired
this entire course. And we've only we've
only touched a few of them. And by the
end of our three weeks, we will have
covered them all. So, that was the tweet
in December. And then there's another
tweet. And this tweet is a long one from
the end of January. And uh I'm I'm not
going to go through all of this, but
just just to he sort of plucks out sort
of a train of thought about some of the
things that are really on his mind about
how agentic coding is is really shaping
up. He says uh in terms of the workflow,
he's gone from being 80% in the manual
autocomplete world with 20% in agents
now to 80% agents, 20% edits and
touching up. That is the shift that he's
been through. That's the first section
coding workflow. And the next section is
on the sort of agent swarms movement.
And he says the no need for IDE anymore
hype. and the agent swarm hype is too
much for me right now. The models
definitely make mistakes. If you have
any code you actually care about, I
would watch them like a hawk. I could
not agree more. So, this is this is
similar to saying that this new sort of
2026 movement is perhaps ahead of its
time and when it comes to serious
coding, you still want to be all over
what's going on. Even if you're yoloing,
you're still watching like a hawk to to
quote Andre. And the third point now I'm
on the top of the of the right hand
column there is about tenacity. It's so
interesting to watch. He says how agents
just work relentlessly. They never get
tired. They never get demoralized. They
just keep going. And next up is speedups
which is where he's saying that he's not
sure how to how to measure the
productivity improvement. He feels net
way faster but the main effect is he
does a lot more than he was going to do.
So he's sort of saying it's like when
people presumably people often ask him
what is it? Is it 10x? Is it 2x? What is
it? It's a hard one to answer. It feels
like there's more output. It's not clear
what what how how to put that in terms
of a velocity. He says not not it's a
speed up but possibly a lot more about
an expansion.
Uh and then then he talks about about
the leverage that they give you the
ability to to meet bigger goals putting
it in a loop that the power of the loop.
And then a one that's quite surprising
which which as he as he acknowledges is
one that that people have very different
views on is the fun element that he says
for him he didn't anticipate that agent
programming feels more fun because
basically they they take care of the
drudgery they take care of the stuff
like getting stuck on something and
bashing your head against a wall. Um and
he says that that LLM coding splits up
engineers. There are some that love it
and some that that hate it. And he
thinks perhaps that maps to people who
like coding and people who primarily
liked building. And presumably he's he's
learning himself as a builder, someone
who gets satisfaction from building
stuff rather than just typing out code
and running it. That might be the
distinction. And some people get their
pleasure from one versus the other. And
that might affect whether you enjoy the
experience of vibe coding. And then two
final points on the bottom right there
which are both fascinating. One of them
atrophy is saying that he's seeing
himself starting to lose his technical
acumen. It's is his uh his ability to
write code. It's it's he's falling out
of practice because he's sort of
allowing the AI to to do do the show.
And that's certainly a risk we all want
to think about. It's it's something I
felt myself too. It's more for me that
that I just it the temptation just to
constantly fire back at the agents and I
and I have a sense of of friction if I
then have to go and read the code once
I've got used to just running with
claude code. So it's a very interesting
point indeed. And then the last one I
don't know how to pronounce this slop
apocalypse. Slop apocalypse. Try saying
that. Uh, so he's saying that that he's
bracing for the year that LLM slop just
goes everywhere and it's, you know, it's
something we've all got to prepare
ourselves for. I think as we saw last
time when we were looking at the
Jellyfin uh write up, I think we're
going to see a backlash against people
delivering slop and a need for code that
gets contributed to be concise and not
to have emojis all over long readmes and
so on. And so I think we're going to see
that kind of that that backlash and a
and a movement towards code that is
clearly not slop, but this is going to
be a big part of 2026. So I wanted to
share this cuz I felt this was
fascinating. It's really like off-the-
cuff train of thought and it fascinates
with me a lot. I I'm I'm also like
Claude Co is definitely uh where I spend
most of my time and it's where we'll be
spending the next two weeks and uh yeah,
a lot of this rings true for me in a big
way. Okay, with that I'm going to do
what I sometimes do which is annoying of
me. I want to do a quick recap of some
of the material we already covered
yesterday. And you might be thinking but
we already did that. But still it's so
important that I want to go through it a
second time but very quickly just to
really hammer home some of the key
points about the right way to vibe code
for success. So the headline that I told
you last time was that you need to be
the boss. That is the key to success and
you need to invest in your agents.m MD
or equivalent be concise but go through
the spec what you want the style how you
want it built and what will success look
like you want to start simple and work
incrementally testing constantly
validating success criteria and don't
get lazy challenge demand evidence or as
Andre says watch it like a hawk and then
always be on top of what's going on and
then handle frust frustration which
which Audrey doesn't mention this but
but uh when when you do find yourself
hitting the same problem again and again
figure out how to just take a step back
do things differently this is the new
way of working and and dealing with with
LLMs that mess up that's that's part of
the journey and I said last time that
interestingly these rules apply both to
junior people coming into this
relatively fresh and to senior engineers
just perhaps in a slightly different way
for junior engineers is it's about using
this as an opportunity to learn and
being skeptical even though you're
you're sort of learning from something
that knows more than you about this
topic. You still want to treat it as
something that's unproven as if you are
a non-technical manager that's been put
in charge of a bunch of people who are
very enthusiastic, very eager, but not
necessarily always right. They sometimes
jump to conclusions. They in their
eagerness, they sometimes trip up over
each other. And so your job is to be the
probing manager who even though you
don't have the same level of technical
depth, you can ask the challenging
questions. You can say, "Give me the
evidence for this. Have you thought
about this? Show me this. Explain this
to me." And you can say, you know, like
managers sometimes do this where they
say, "This might be a silly question,
but perhaps you could explain to me."
And then they ask a really pointed,
insightful question. You're like, "Oh my
goodness." That's what you have to do.
That's your job. And if you're a senior
manager, then it's about figuring out
how you can work effectively in this new
way of doing things. Less coding, more
building, to use Andre's expression. And
and so get into the this the sense of
this is the new craft. And then do the
building and figure out how to make that
work for you so that you're enjoying it.
Maybe like Andre, you're going to enjoy
it even more once you find your groove
with this and realize that you can you
can expand, you can deliver more
capability in the same time through the
use of these agents and they can take
care of the stuff that was perhaps
mundane before. So figuring out that
balance but then yes always taking
advantage of your expertise to be also
like challenging making sure that that
uh that everything is being thought
through and and never never letting it
be never never getting lazy and just
letting it do its thing. Always watch it
like a hawk. And that leads to the
summary point which is have a healthy
balanced attitude towards this. Expect
mixed results. Don't get caught up in
the hype. Don't get caught up in the 10x
build whatever you want. Sit back. You
can yolo your way to to building a
complete product. It's not true. And if
you think that, then you're just going
to get frustrated and you're going to
hit a wall. So instead, recognize that
there is a an incredible upside of this.
But there's also a downside. Expect that
and then work incrementally and slowly
so so that you build things in a
realistic, reasonable way. And as long
as that's where your head is at, then
you're going to absolutely love this.